Inventory of the Cuban Freedom Committee records
Hoover Institution Archives
- The Cuban Revolution at 30, the Cuban American National Foundation, 1989 (Box 26)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, radio broadcast sound recordings, open reel tapes, circa 1960s (Box 26)
  - "Entrevista a dos personas jóvenes sobre programas en Cuba,", circa 1960s (Box 26)
  - "Mensaje de la Srta. Juanita Castro sobre la irresponsabilidad comunista en relación con los preparativos del pueblo ante el azote del huracán,", circa 1960s (Box 26)
  - "Estudio del "Diario del 'Che' Guevara en Bolivia,", 1968 (Box 26)
- American Indians, United States Information Agency, 1962-1983 (Box 27)
- New Mexico universities, 1977-1980 (Box 27)
- Admissions information for universities, prospectus brochures, 1965-1973 (Box 27)
- United States Department of State, conference consortium directors, photographs, October 1977 (Box 27)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, "In the Press," publications, 1961 (Box 27)
- Partners of the Americas, university linkage program, circa 1980s (Box 27)
- Religion and Revolution: Cuba and Nicaragua, Margaret Crahan, 1986 (Box 27)
- Latin American Information Committee, 1961- 1963 (Box 27)
- CIA involvement in Radio Free Cuba, 1967 (Box 27)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, "In the Press," publications, 1961-1962 (Box 28)
- "Rocinante Gordo por Eugenio Sánchez Torrento," poem, 1971-1973 (Box 28)
- International Exchange of Persons: A Reassessment, American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1976 (Box 28)
- Of Human Rights, Georgetown University, 1983-1985 (Box 28)
- Special Report: Human Rights in Cuba, United States Department of State, Americas Watch, Amnesty International, Inter-American Commission on Human Rights, 1990 (Box 28)
- Album Azul de Cuba: This Is the True History of Cuba, Aurelio Garcia Dulzaides, 1965 (Box 28)
- Bohemia, Cuban magazine, 1961 (Box 28)
- Verde Olivo: Organo de las Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias, Cuban magazine, circa 1960s (Box 28)
- "Hispanic-American Educators," United States International Communication Agency, 1979-1983 (Box 28)
- US Books Abroad: Neglected Ambassadors, United States Information Agency, Library of Congress, 1980-1984 (Box 28)
- International baccalaureate program, Washington International School, 1974-1980 (Box 28)
- Cuban Freedom Committee, radio broadcast sound recordings, open reel tapes, 1963 (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a Candido Arencibia, María Luisa Ruiz, José Martínez,", circa 1960s (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a Modesto García Tabacalero, Juan Fernández, Adalberto José Pérez, Chofer de Alquiler,", circa 1960s (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a José López, 30 años, después del flora,", 28 October 1963 (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a dos Cubanos matanzas y las villas, relatos de los campamentos rusos," WKFW, 18 September 1962 (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a dos Uruguayos, vienen de la embajada de Uruguay, para hoy- es muy importante pues todas las madres han sido dejadas en Cuba," WKWF Key West, 1:32am, 14 June 1963 (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a madre y otro que llegaron en bote, la forma en que vinieron, la situacion en Cuba, los alzado en Cuba y la falta de ayuda, faltan armas y zapatos,", 20 September 1963 (Box 29)
  - "Entrevista a Dr. George Hernandez, MD, llego de la embajada de Ecuador, via Puerto Rico, acogido al amparo de Brazil,", 11 February 1963 (Box 29)
- Index contact cards from office, circa 1960s (Box 29)
- Programs for minorities, expenditures by state, 1978-1980 (Box 29)
- The Advertising Council (2 folders), 1961 (Box 30)
- Cold War propaganda hearings (2 folders), September 1963 (Box 30)
- Book list "LAIC" and others, 1962-1966 (Box 30)
- Cold War propaganda hearings, 1965-1966 (Box 30)
- Tobe listed name-address to MCA, 1967 (Box 30)
- Argentine Embassy, 1965 (Box 30)
- Free Cuba Radio personnel, 1965-1968 (Box 30)
- Rimiguez, 1967 (Box 30)
- Sanchez T. Eugenio, 14 September 1967 (Box 30)
- Movimiento Obrero Bajo el Regimen, July 1967 (Box 30)
- Free Cuba Radio, employee policy, 1966 (Box 30)
- Cuban Freedom Committee programming, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
- Coton, J. M., 1967 (Box 30)
- Dulzaides, Luiz, 1962 (Box 30)
- Dr. Casariego (II), 1962 (Box 30)
- Cepeda, Osvaldo, 1963 (Box 30)
- Margarita Prieto, 1966 (Box 30)
- Maria L. Guerrero, 1965-1967 (Box 30)
- Rosa G. Arias, undated (Box 30)
- Garcia Huerta (III), 1964 (Box 30)
- Mario Barrera, 1963, 1967 (Box 30)
- Cuba national holiday, May-June 1963 (Box 30)
- Basic Documents of the History of the United States of America (Documentos Basicos de la Historia de Los Estados Unidos de America), circa 1960 (Box 30)
- Gil Manuel, WWL, 1964-1967 (Box 30)
- Perez, Joe, 1965-1967 (Box 30)
- Foreign policy association, 1965-1966 (Box 30)
- Senators and Representatives, US Congress, 1963-1967 (Box 31)
- "Fechas de Independencia," Dr. P. Vilá, 1964-1965 (Box 31)
- Freedom House, 1966-1967 (Box 31)
- Freedom Studies Center, 1966 (Box 31)
- Newsmen, 1966 (Box 31)
- Questions, interviews, commentary, circa 1960s (Box 31)
- Republican National Committee, 1967 (Box 31)
- Material for speeches (2 folders), circa 1960s (Box 31)
- Congressional record clippings, April-May 1966 (Box 31)
- United States businessmen, groups, 1964-1965 (Box 31)
- United States policy, statements, news, etc., 1961-1965 (Box 31)
- Senators and Representatives, U.S. Congress, speeches (2 folders), 1962-1967 (Box 32)
- United States policy, statements, news, etc. (3 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 32)
- Newspapers and magazines, 1965-1967 (Box 32)
- African-American groups, Carmichael, clippings, 1961-1967 (Box 32)
- Three Faces of Cuba, 1965-1967 (Box 33)
- Newspapers and magazines (5 folders), 1961-1965 (Box 33)
- Mariada Arensberg letters, 1961-1968 (Box 33)
- Contacts for groups, collaborators, and individuals in the United States, 1967 (Box 33)
- Radio Free Cuba, public relations, announcements, 1965-1967 (Box 33)
- Cuban International radio broadcasting, hours and operations, 1967 (Box 33)
- Time Magazine, "Cuba: The Decaying Revolution,", 8 October 1965 (Box 33)
- Propaganda materials, edited by other groups, sent to listeners (Material de propagananda, editado por otros grupos, que nosotros enviamo a nuestros oyentes), 1964-1968 (Box 34)
- Lists of recommended people (Listas de personas recomendadas), 1963-1967 (Box 34)
- Meeting of consultation of foreign ministers, 12 January 1962 (Box 34)
- Hoover Institution research correspondence, 1964 (Box 34)
- "Unthinkable Thoughts," Senator J. William Fulbright, radio announcement transcript, 1964 (Box 34)
- "Cuba necesita de la ayuda de las republicas hermanas para Poder Liberarse del Comunismo," radio announcement transcript, 18 June 1964 (Box 34)
- Thomas Mann speech, 18 November 1964 (Box 34)
- Mailing list of civic organizations, circa 1960s (Box 34)
- Reprint of speech by Hon. Roman C. Pucinski, Tri-Continental Conference, 20 January 1966 (Box 34)
- Special list for Pucinski's speech, 26 July 1966 (Box 34)
- Speech by Rep. Roman Pucinski, 26 July 1967 (Box 34)
- Labor organizations leaders in Latin America, 1964 (Box 34)
- Mariada Arensberg speech, Advertising Council of America, board of directors' meeting, 21 April 1966 (Box 34)
- Radio stations that carried Cuban Freedom Committee public service announcements, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- TV Stations that carried Cuban Freedom Committee public service announcements, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- List of donors to Cuban Freedom Committee, 1963 (Box 35)
- Mailing list of labor organizations and leaders in Latin America, 1964 (Box 35)
- Mailing list of Organization of American States (OAS) press, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- Directory of African-American newspapers, magazines, and periodicals, 1964 (Box 35)
- Special list for releases from the Cuban Freedom Committee, 1964 (Box 35)
- Newspapers and magazines of the Caribbean, 1963 (Box 35)
- Spanish language newspapers and magazines in the U.S. list, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- Mailing list for Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- List of national and international labor unions and publications in the U.S., 1964 (Box 35)
- African-American programming, 1964 (Box 35)
- Mailing list for labor groups, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- List of English language newspapers in Latin America, 1966 (Box 35)
- Mailing of speech by Hon. Roman C. Pucinski, Tri-Continental Conference, 1966 (Box 35)
- 50,000 watt radio stations in the U.S., list, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- African-American colleges and radio stations, 1963 (Box 35)
- Santo Domingo, correspondent, 1962-1966 (Box 35)
- Santo Domingo, project, 1962-1963 (Box 35)
- Eduardo Reyes Cerda, Organizacion Americana de Universitarios Anticomunistas, 1962-1967 (Box 35)
- Radio Santo Domingo, 1962-1963 (Box 35)
- Radio Caribe, daily reports, 1962-1965 (Box 35)
- Radio Santo Domingo, daily reports, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
- Radio station WKWF, 1961-1966 (Box 36)
- Radio Habana, Cuba, 1961-1967 (Box 36)
- Radio WWL, New Orleans (2 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 36)
- Radio Santo Domingo (2 folders), 1962-1965 (Box 36)
- Monitoring survey, Key West, Florida, 1965 (Box 36)
- Reorganization Committee, 1967 (Box 36)
- Radio Santo Domingo, daily reports (2 folders), 1965 (Box 36)
- Record of tapes sent to WWL and Latin America, 1965-1966 (Box 36)
- Radio station WGBS (2 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 36)
- Communist Propaganda Organizations and Activities in Latin America, United States Information Agency, Office of Policy and Research, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
- Cuba: A Communications Fact Book, 1961 (Box 36)
- Communist broadcasts to Latin America, 1967 (Box 37)
- Radio Free Europe, 1964 (Box 37)
- Radio WWL, WKWF, Joe Perez, 1964-1966 (Box 37)
- Ragio station WGBS, 1962- 1963 (Box 37)
- Free Cuba Radio, programming, stations schedules, and content, 1964-1966 (Box 37)
- Badillo y Berges, Santo Domingo, 1963-1964 (Box 37)
- Ray Cromley, daily news, 1965-1967 (Box 37)
- Advisory Board correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 37)
- Mariada Arensberg, testimony, 1963-1964 (Box 37)
- Collaborators with Cuban Freedom Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 37)
- Canada and Italy, 1967 (Box 37)
- Latin America (2 folders), 1966 (Box 37)
- Latin American groups (2 folders), September 1967 (Box 38)
- Thermofax copies of letters (Copias de Cartas Tiradas en thermofax) (2 folders), 1963-1965 (Box 38)
- Radio stations listener surveys, 1962-1968 (Box 38)
- United States groups, 1967 (Box 38)
- Cuban listeners in the United States (Radio Escuchas Cubanos en los Estados Unidos), 1967 (Box 38)
- List of students, professors, and young people who listen and collaborate with Cuban Freedom Committee, 1965 (Box 39)
- List of letters received, sent, and brochures (Control de Cartas Recibidas, Enviadas, y Folletos), 1967 (Box 39)
- Copies of Letters documenting the outrage from the end of the Transmissions (Copias de Cartas Indignado por que se Acabaron las Transmisiones), 1967 (Box 39)
- Interviews (2 folders), circa 1960s (Box 39)
- Memoranda (2 folders), 1965-1966 (Box 39)
- WGBS, daily report, 1961-1966 (Box 40)
  - 1961-1964 (10 folders) (Box 40)
  - 1964-1966 (16 folders) (Box 41)
- Letters from listeners, groups, and individuals, 1967 (Box 41)
- Monthly report, April 1967 (Box 42)
- Quarterly report, October-December 1966 (Box 42)
- Radio stations, questionnaire, 1962-1967 (Box 42)
- WGBS, daily report (6 folders), 1966-1967 (Box 42)
- Report for Cuban Freedom Committee by Robert R. Mullen and Company, Public Relations (Box 42)
  - January-June 1965 (Box 42)
  - July-December 1965 (Box 42)
- Monthly report, November 1963 (Box 42)
- Advisory board invitations, sent and not answered, 1961 (Box 43)
- Contracts, UPI and others, 1961-1967 (Box 43)
- Contracts for WWL, Katz Agency, 1962-1967 (Box 43)
- Special letters, Cuba, 1965 (Box 43)
- Monthly Report, 1963-1967 (Box 43)
  - July 1963-August 1964 (11 folders) (Box 43)
  - September 1964-August 1965 (12 folders) (Box 44)
  - September 1965-October 1966 (14 folders) (Box 45)
  - 1966-March 1967 (5 folders) (Box 46)
- Free Cuba Radio, programming and policy, 1961-1967 (Box 46)
- Termination letters, 1967 (Box 46)
- Reports for Cuban Freedom Committee, by Robert R. Mullen and Company, Public Relations (7 folders) (Box 46)
  - August 1961-December 1964 (Box 46)
  - November 1960-July 1961 (Box 47)
  - January 1966-December 1966 (Box 47)
- United States groups, circa 1960s.; See also box 56 (Box 47)
  - BAL-E (11 folders), circa 1960s (Box 47)
  - FA-O (19 folders), circa 1960s (Box 48)
  - PA-Z (17 folders), circa 1960s (Box 49)
- Letters from listeners, 1961-1967 (Box 50)
  - Cuba, Radio Free Cuba (12 folders), 1961-1962 (Box 50)
  - WWL (2 folders), January-February 1963 (Box 51)
  - Radio Caribe, February-March 1963 (Box 51)
  - WGBS, February 1963 (Box 51)
  - WKWF, February 1963 (Box 51)
- Groups, 1962-1968. (Box 51)
  Arranged by country
  - Argentina, 1963-1967 (Box 51)
  - Bolivia, 1962-1967 (Box 51)
  - Brasil, 1961-1967 (Box 51)
  - Canada, 1964-1967 (Box 51)
  - Colombia (2 folders), 1963-1967 (Box 52)
  - Costa Rica, 1963-1967 (Box 52)
  - Chile, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Dominican Republic (2 folders), 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Ecuador, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - El Salvador, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Guatemala, 1966-1967 (Box 52)
  - Haiti, 1963-1964 (Box 52)
  - Honduras, A-L, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Honduras, M-V, 1962-1968 (Box 53)
  - Honduras britanicas, 1965 (Box 53)
  - Jamaica, 1965 (Box 53)
  - Nicaragua, 1965-1967 (Box 53)
  - Panama, 1964-1966 (Box 53)
  - Paraguay, 1964-1967 (Box 53)
  - Peru, 1962-1967 (Box 53)
  - Puerto Rico, 1961-1966 (Box 53)
  - Uruguay, 1961-1966 (Box 53)
  - Venezuela, 1961-1967 (Box 53)
- Letters from listeners, 1963-1967 (Box 53)
- Listeners, Antilles, Aruba, Curacao, Martinique, Bahamas, Virgin Islands, 1961-1965 (Box 53)
- Copias de cartas de Cuba para maquina copiadora, 1967 (Box 53)
- Copies of letters, 1966 (Box 54)
- Letters on sabotage in Cuba, 1963-1965 (Box 54)
- Excerpts of letters used in the hearing of the sub-committee, September 1963 (Box 54)
- Response to our letter to Latin America (Respuestas a Nuestra Circular a America Latina), 1963 (Box 54)
  - April 1963 (Box 54)
  - February 1963 (Box 54)
- Response to our letter requesting support to Venezuela's demand before the OAS, December 1963 (Box 54)
- Response to our letter in support of Venezuela's demands (Respuestas a nuestra circular en apoyo de las demandas de Venezuela antes), June 1964 (Box 54)
- Lions and rotary clubs in Latin America, 1964 (Box 54)
- Directory of stations comprising the Inter-American Association of broadcasters in Latin America (Directorio de Emisoras que integran la Asociación Interamericana de Radiodifusión en la America Latina), June 1965 (Box 55)
- Circular letter to the Inter-American Association of broadcasters in Latin America (Asociacin Interamericana de Radiodifusin), 1965 (Box 55)
- Response to our March letter and brochure 'Castro attempt' to listeners and Venezuelan groups (Respuesta a nuestra Circular de Marzo a Oyentes y Grupos de Venezuela, enviado folleto "Intentona Castrista,"), 1966 (Box 55)
- Response to our January letter on journalists to journalists in Latin America (Respuesta a nuestra Circular de Enero a los periodistas de America Latina, sobre periodistas), 1966 (Box 55)
- Response to our February letter to the Asociación Interamericana de Radiodifusión en la America Latina members, 1966 (Box 55)
- Circular letter to bishops and archbishops Latin America, February 1967 (Box 55)
- Circular sent to groups and listeners in Bolivia, Colombia, Guatemala, Peru, and Venezuela, 1967 (Box 55)
- Letters sent to members of the Asociación Interamericana de Radiodifusión in Bolivia, Guatemala, Columbia, Peru, and Venezuela, 1967 (Box 55)
- Presentation 'College Journalists' sent to 139 newspapers and 269 radio stations of the Asociación Interamericana de Radiodifusión, June 1967 (Box 55)
- Control sheets, 1962-1966 (Box 55)
- French translations of "Alerta Pueblos de America" and "Cuba Hoy en Día,", circa 1960s (Box 55)
- Letters for publicity, 1962-1966 (Box 55)
- Statistics of the Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 55)
- Record of pamphlet printings, 1961-1967 (Box 55)
- Maps, Cuba, Caribbean, South and Central America, circa 1960s (Box 56)
- Cuban Freedom Committee photographs, 1961-1965 (Box 56)
- United States, groups Ab-Av (4 folders), 1963-1967.; See also box 47-49 (Box 56)
- Mexico groups, 1961-1969 (Box 57)
  - A-Fue (15 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 57)
  - G-Paz (20 folders), 1961-1968 (Box 58)
  - Ped-Z (16 folders), 1961-1969 (Box 59)
- Cuba listener letters, 1963-1967 (Box 60)
  - January-June 1963 (8 folders) (Box 60)
  - July 1963-February 1964 (9 folders) (Box 61)
  - March 1964-December 1964 (11 folders) (Box 62)
  - January 1965-November 1965 (11 folders) (Box 63)
  - December 1965-October 1966 (11 folders) (Box 64)
  - November 1966-August 1967 (9 folders) (Box 65)
- Oscar Reyes, Cuban Radio man, 1963-1966 (Box 65)
- LIFE Magazine (3 folders), 1961- 1963 (Box 66)
- Letters sent by Cuban Freedom Committee (18 folders), 1964-1965 (Box 66)
- American Security Council interviews Cuban Freedom Committee, vinyl records, 28 October 1964 (Box 66)
- Fidel Castro speeches, 1961-1963.; See also boxes 8-9, 68 (Box 67)
  - December 1961 (Box 67)
  - Mar-November 1962 (Box 67)
  - September-November 1962 (Box 67)
  - January- April 1963 (Box 67)
  - May-August 1963 (Box 67)
  - November-December 1963 (Box 67)
- Radio Transworld, Netherlands Antilles, 1962-1966 (Box 68)
- Subversion, Comisiòn Especial de Seguridad (4 folders), 1965-1967 (Box 68)
- Cuban economy (3 folders), 1964-1968 (Box 68)
- "Cuba Clandestina,", 1963-1965 (Box 68)
- Fidel Castro speeches, September-October 1963.; See also boxes 8-9, 67 (Box 68)
- U.S. magazines about Cuba, 1962-1990 (Box 68)
- Bay of Pigs, 1961-1966 (Box 69)
- "La Historia Me Absolverá" competition, 1964-1967 (Box 69)
- Subversion, Comisiòn Especial de Seguridad, 1964 (Box 69)
- Organization of American States, final act of Rio conference, 1965 (Box 69)
- Political, Economic and Social Thought of Fidel Castro, 1959 (Box 69)
- Historial Obrero Cubano 1574-1965, Mario Riera Hernandez (Box 69)
- "Sketch of Frederic Fernandez Cavada, a native of Cuba, 1871,", 1963 (Box 69)
- In Memoriam Elena Mederos de Gonzalez, 1981 (Box 69)
- "The Power of the Democratic Idea," Rockefeller panel report on American democracy, 1960 (Box 69)
- Analisis del Marxismo, Ediciones Gallo, 1963 (Box 69)
- Cuban purges, 1966 (Box 70)
- Cuban exodus, Camarioca airlift (2 folders), 1965 (Box 70)
- United States Cuban refugee program, 1963-1966 (Box 70)
- Cuban prisons (2 folders), 1961-1967 (Box 70)
- Sugar production, 1961-1967 (Box 70)
- Cuban listener reactions with intelligence on USSR military in Cuba, 1962 (Box 71)
- Cuban education, 1962-1965 (Box 71)
- Cuban military school, 1964-1966 (Box 71)
- Cuban missiles, 1963-1966 (Box 71)
- Cuban health, 1966-1967 (Box 71)
- Cuban intellectuals, 1966 (Box 71)
- The Cuban Report, Directorio Revolucionario Estudiantil, 1962-1967 (Box 71)
- Cuba, general, 1959-1964 (Box 71)